foreign
[Applause]
so uh when I used to come with my friend
Mama Christie
uh
she would uh we would be on the airplane
back and she'd whisper to me that was so
cool you know when I say what she say
learning the gear
and I'd say well yeah that's cool and
she said but the leader from Krishna I
said
I know Christian had to talk again she
said no no you don't understand it's
Mommy swallowing banana is Krishna
and we've got it straight from Krishna
so I figured we better play a song for
Krishna on the last night
music
[Applause]
[Music]
foreign
[Applause]
[Music]
Krishna
Krishna Krishna
[Music]
put it on
a mother
[Music]
Christmas
Christian
[Music]
ity
thank you
[Music]
get out of my
mind
[Music]
again
please
[Music]
foreign
Krishna
Krishna Krishna
knowing the Giants
foreign
[Applause]
one time
[Music]
I know
tonight
today
times
foreign
[Applause]
[Music]
foreign
so just to review uh yesterday uh
it was really important in the history
of philosophy but anyway I think
not because
it's very difficult to reconcile the
lower school of Buddhism in the highest
School of Buddhism aren't that question
of what happens when you reach nirvana
and you see because the lower school is
saying oh you don't have you escape the
cycle of rebirth and then the higher
school is saying uh no no you uh
you stop your questions your mental
afflictions you see but really it's the
same thing
you see because what you're seeing right
now
is governed
mainly by the negative thoughts we've
had in your in your life and your past
lives so the fact that you have to die
in this world
the fact that you've seen War
on Hunger
or conflict is
is coming from you as much as the pen
okay as much as the guy who's yelling at
you every experience in your world is
coming from you
and from your negative emotions and then
we were saying all along
that the only way to stop them
your your negative emotions is to see
Ultimate Reality it's the only way okay
the other you can think of this person
who's yelling at me is going to pass
sooner or later or you can think that I
can't really control the situation or
you can try to turn a bad situation into
some kind of temporary Advantage right
you can struggle to reinterpret the bad
things in your life as something useful
and those are nice spiritual things to
do but they don't solve the problem
right those are just dealing with the
problems and not removing the problem so
every spiritual method which which
teaches how to deal with a problem
is is considered in in this thinking not
to be uh real teaching
to say oh stand there while the guy
yells at you and sooner or later he will
start off or smile and make the best of
it or try to see that something better
is happening right reinterpret all the
bad things that happened here
and then in this school there's a
different approach they're saying let's
make them things that never happen
and then you don't have to be patient
with them
and you don't have to and reinterpret
them and you don't have to learn how to
cope with them they'll learn how to cope
with bad things
arrange it so that they never happen
and then you don't have to cope with
anything
in this system you'll try in Nirvana
you're trying to remove forever
just all the bad things that happened
here okay in advance in advance you
prevent them from happening okay that's
the idea to do that you have to
understand what Ultimate Reality is and
we said yesterday
that Ultimate Reality was the absence of
something something missing like your
credit card at the restaurant right
like you thought it was there but it's
not there okay
so what is missing uh
in a in a usable example of Ultimate
Reality okay like in a in an example
that we can all really use in our own
lives where is the Ultimate Reality and
we said someone who calls you
okay someone who calls your kid is that
Ben Tao in Chinese in the bank call I
like it in a stupid mouth and then calm
see me that Ben call
and uh
and they say you're stupid you know
you're a stupid person and then um
the natural reaction is to say no you're
stupid you answer with your stupid by
saying that you plant another seed in
your mind and you will meet another
stupid person in the future okay so you
can remember that the next time swamiji
started out the whole uh
all teaching on the Gita by saying that
the highest Dharma is forbearance when
someone is injuring you or or insulting
you you see and here's a real method you
can use
you can look at them and say
you know uh well this person is coming
from me and if I respond in a negative
way I will have to meet them again
so if you don't like somebody what's the
best way to get rid of them
just be quiet don't respond you see
don't make new Karma you see you can't
eliminate all the enemies in your heart
it's possible and you don't need a gun
say it's hunting in trouble I did it I
had 800 people working in my building in
New York and I one by one I
I cleaned them out
one day the accountant came to me he
said everybody's staying till 9 pm
they're cheating you I said no no you
check the time cards
and then he checked he said they all say
five o'clock but they're all saved
online
and and I said I know and he said well
why are they staying till 9 o'clock
because they don't get paid from five
o'clock to nine o'clock I said they love
it here they want us there
you know I cleaned out the whole place
800 people
you know you can do it it's very strange
the whole ashram is harmonious then
and you know my name is poor you you
know you work on people one by one you
say this person's irritating so I'm
going to stop being irritated
you know or this person can't keep the
beat on the song so I'm gonna practice a
little bit more
that's how you get rid of people you
don't like okay that's the only way you
do the opposite Karma
and you clean them up okay so then
that's one way to think about it but
yesterday I was asking that you tried to
do a meditation
in which you imagined
that the last person that you insulted
you you tried to examine
whether they are coming from their own
side right is the person
coming from their own side what and what
did we say are they coming this way or
this way
yeah just do it do it once it's good
luck okay
to your wife or husband
get out
but you can this means he's coming for
you this means it's coming from his own
side all right this means I'm not to
blame this means I created him got it
this means I'm not to blame this means
I'm creating the afternoon all right
so now that the tricky thing if you want
to reach Ultimate Reality if you want a
taste of Ultimate Reality wrestling
right it's just
focus on the next person who insults you
and see if they're coming from try to
find a guy who's coming from his own
side
try to find the guy who's coming from
his own side and what will happen
you won't find anything he's not there
he never was there all right but the one
you get angry at is the one who comes
from his own side or the one who's
coming from you
it's the one who you think is coming
from his own side you see you cannot be
angry as a person
if you understand that they're coming
from you you can't be angry at them you
would be angry at
just stop you're the only the only
person to blame is yourself in any
situation Always Forever okay there was
never any other person who to blame if
the guy is calling you stupid it can
only be because you did that
all right if you didn't do that he
wouldn't call me stupid he couldn't call
you stupid he wouldn't be there in the
ashram
you brought him here
okay and you made him say everything he
says
see you gotta get that I'm not saying
reflect on the fact that he came from
you think listen carefully I'm saying
try to see that he's not even there
okay try to see that the guy you thought
was there was never there the guy that
wasn't your right the guy that
wasn't your fault doesn't exist
does he exist
that's the guy that's a diamond called
exists
he tried to grasp try to work with that
why that's very close to Ultimate
Reality that is the absence of the guy
who's not your fault is Ultimate Reality
that is Ultimate Reality the absence of
a guy who never was there and could not
be there is Ultimate Reality and if you
see it you're liberating you achieve
Moksha okay get a taste for it get a
test part all right so rather than
focusing on the guy and saying oh he's
coming from me which you can do and it's
true
rather focus on the guy and say the guy
I thought was there is nothing
and I was getting angry at Phantoms my
whole life my whole life every person I
ever disliked was a phantom wasn't there
they just weren't there so get used to
them because that could flip you into
the Vega County the the perception of
the direct perception of Ultimate
Reality okay because he's that's close
that's the closest you can get uh with a
conceptual State of Mind to the direct
procession of Ultimate Reality focus on
people you don't like
and realize that they don't exist
okay so but we're going to practice
something all right we're going to
practice something
this comes from a llama named
kid song love song he was born in 1689
lucky for you he attended the greatest
Monastery in the world
uh which is called Sarah May
okay uh
he was a geisha from Santa May that's my
Monastery
and he he had a very beautiful thing he
said there are four ways that things go
okay about ultimate if you wanna no
we're gonna do a little Ultimate Reality
we're going to talk a little bit about
ultimately
tonight okay and somehow that's going to
lead to love
okay by the end to compassion all right
so here we go
[Music]
he said there are four ways in which you
can see let's take the guy who calls you
stupid since he's been around for a few
days now okay or maybe longer
um
he said there are four possibilities
going on about how you see him and if
you want the goodest emptiness
meditation this is it okay it's a
beautiful
a beautiful piece he said number one
uh
he
he looks like a guy calling you stupid
and you take him to be that way
all right I'll say it again he looks
like a guy calling you stupid and you
take him to be that way is that correct
or incorrect
careful be careful listen to them yeah
good he said that much is correct okay
there's no problem yet all I said is a
gun is calling you stupid and you're and
you take him to be that way he's a guy
calling you stupid there's a guy calling
you stupid we didn't make a mistake yet
and there's no Nvidia yet and everything
is pramana so far
everything is the correct perception so
far there is a guy standing there he is
calling you stupid and you he appears to
be that way and you take him to be that
way all permanent all correct perception
no problem there there is a guy there
you can say illusion Maya all you want
the guy is irritating yes
that part is real okay you have to
understand this part and then you'll get
to Ultimate Reality I'm Gonna Get Fuzzy
what do you calling
warm and fuzzy in a few minutes
but I want this is for the ashram people
okay this is the meat of the matter
that's number one not
ice
um
[Music]
he seems to be coming from his own side
and you hold him to be that way got it
and you hold him to be that way you take
him you take it to be that he decided to
call you stupid and that that's his
choice and his decision and his will
is to call you stupid and that's and
that's why he's coming he appears to be
acting on his own accord on his own
willpower and it appears that way and he
accept that that's the case
is that correct
neither neither half is correct good
thanks again okay that's more difficult
neither half is correct what
he's appearing to come from his own side
and you taking him to come from his own
side are both wrong got it so in number
two both sides are wrong he looks to be
running on his own
rather than one
coming from your son's cars coming from
your common sense he looks to be running
on his own but he's not he looks to be
running on his own and you take it to be
that way okay from his side he appears
to be running on his own from your side
you take it to be that way that's number
two okay both are wrong
so so far we're gonna have a quick
example
is there a stupid guy up there calling
you stupid yeah does he appear to be
calling you stupid yes if you take him
to because you're making a mistake yes
foreign
[Music]
if you take him to be that way is that
okay yeah he's there he's calling you
stupid okay second step
he appears to be calling you stupid from
his own will but he wants to call you
stupid he's right from his side
and you take him to be calling you
stupid from his own will is that correct
no you mean him you created him you
forced him to come to the Joshua
and and you have created every word he
said
it appears the opposite but it's not
it appears that way and you take it to
be that way those are two mistakes got
it okay we finished two here comes the
third one you notice that they come in
Paris
right he appears to be a guy calling you
stupid and you take him to be a guy
called me stupid that's okay
he appears to be coming got a guy is
calling you stupid from his own side and
you take him to be a guy who's calling
you stupid find his own side that's
those are both smart guy you okay so far
yeah okay now it gets worse foreign
yeah
suddenly you grasp that there's no guy
calling you stupid who's not your fault
and he no longer appears to be calling a
guy
a guy calling you stupid who's not your
fault got it I'll say it again
suddenly he no longer appears to be a
guy who is not your fault and suddenly
you take him not to be a guy who's not
your fault
got it
you corrupt your mistake okay
that's the that's the perception of
Ultimate Reality okay that's the
perception of him he no longer appears
to be coming from his son and you don't
take him to be that way anymore got it
would you like to be at number three
yes why
talk Clayton to me talk question
you can't have a clay shot towards
someone that you know you couldn't okay
unless it's guilty and you're his mom I
mean that's different
I'm just kidding uh if you know you left
the water in the bathroom floor and you
step in it you forgive yourself I mean
that's the way it goes if you know it's
somebody else you get angry okay
in number three I understand he's not
coming from his side he he doesn't even
appear to become from his side anymore
and I don't take him to be that way is
that a good place to be yes yes why
no question you can't get angry you'll
be calm and collected you will fix the
situation okay I must be calling people
stupid
a real Yogi when someone calls him
stupid the first reaction is I must have
done that and they start examining who
themselves and they don't worry about
them
because it doesn't fix them
if you concentrate on yourself that you
say I must have called somebody stupid
last week then they just go away
800 people
in the building downtown
line
for no pain
right you know you you will change your
reality you see your whole reality will
change if you just understand number
three okay he no longer appears to be
coming from his own side and I don't
take him to be coming from the sunset
they want to get to number three okay
number four
number four is just the positive
number four is the positive expression
of number three
okay here we go which is by the way not
Ultimate Reality
it's it's a relative reality
it's a true relative reality okay he
appears to have been produced by my past
deeds and I taken to be that way
got it he appears to have been produced
from my past actions and I take him to
be that way is that positive or negative
it's positive he he is I didn't say he's
not he is coming from my past actions is
that positive or negative
it's positive I didn't say not right
number four is is positive he he appears
to be coming from my past actions and I
take him to be that way and that's
correct okay it's not Ultimate Reality
Ultimate Reality is number three
Ultimate Reality says he is not what I
thought
and he no longer appears that way okay
Ultimate Reality is always negative it
has to be a narrative the only one which
can save you
the only one which can stop your
negative emotions forever is number
three
why
we talked about it driving from the
airport to the dock what's the dog
called Sunshine Yonkers sorry mermaid
you see a beautiful girl you know
standing in the storefront and then you
get out of the car on Sunday you realize
she's a mannequin right yeah then where
does the desire to have her email go
her email address what happens to the
desire to have your email address
it just vanishes it's not there's no
longer Alabama There's no longer any
support for that idea you don't want an
email address from a mannequin
and there won't be any chance that you
will somehow
sleep out you never yes you'll never
answer
so but try to get the feeling and see
what when you have that sudden moment of
realization that she's not human
you can never again ask for her email it
will never cross your mind again
okay it just can't happen
it's the negative thing that's important
okay he's not there the guy calling me
stupid who's not my fault was never
there he's just not there that that
realization is so powerful that you see
that's the direct that's that's Ultimate
Reality and that can get you to know
only number three even number four which
is so cool and so true is not going to
do it by itself
see you can't go to the mannequin and
say oh look she was made in a factory
and she's made out of plastic and that's
not gonna do it it has to be oh my God
she's not a human
she's not a living person she's not at
all what I thought she was got it she's
not a person
all the people you're ever gone angry at
were not people they don't exist
you see if you could get that you just
would never get Angry Anymore
to think oh he's coming from my bad
cities maybe I should be a better person
this
is it's good but it's not it's not
ultimately it's good but it's not the
ultimate thing to Sunday look at this
person saying
the guy I thought hating me is not there
the guy I thought didn't like me it was
never there
then you can't be angry again you just
can't get angry it's not a thing of
trying to convince yourself oh I should
be spiritual I'm not supposed to get
angry I'm in an Armstrong why should I
hate somebody you know
it's not gonna work you see if you can
look at the person and say the person
like the person who's calling me stupid
who's not coming from me was never there
they're just not there then how can you
get angry at them
there's nobody to get angry at you got
it got it okay there's nobody there was
never anybody there every time you ever
got upset in your life
the least bit off balance the person you
were thinking about wasn't there this is
the this is the tragedy of our life
every every doubt you ever had I mean
anger every irritation it'll be slightly
upset at somebody they were all focused
at something that wasn't there
and that's the tragedy of life if so
you've got to try to get to number three
you got to try to get to number two no
one more thing
education Michael always says he's got
like six more things uh
I thought you
we I thought she might like to feel the
difference
between reaching Nirvana sorry three
things
four things
a person who has no clue about Ultimate
Reality number one
number two a person who has seen they've
had that Peak experience and they have
seen Ultimate Reality directly
second case
third case a person who reaches Nirvana
okay fourth case what
a person who reaches Enlightenment I
want to talk about those part really
I'll say it again someone who has no
clue what's going on they're just a
normal person
number two number two if you had a clue
what was going on you could make 100
million dollars in a few years it's not
difficult
you just don't know what you're doing
I'm not kidding a person with no
training and no interest in business can
work part-time and make a hundred
million dollars if you knew what the
hell was going on
okay here we go
number one
person has no clue they don't even think
about it okay
they never came to celebrities Yoga
Center or his gear okay number two the
person work
s they saw they saw Ultimate Reality
directly we call Anya you could say
number three what was that
a person who reached Nevada and then
number four a person who's reached
Fallen like me which is higher than
their mother okay Nirvana is just to get
rid of your anger however
Enlightenment is something beyond that
and we'll talk about it okay so here we
go
how many of those of those people see a
stupid guy there
all four you are so hot tonight
four they all four see a guy calling
somebody stupid all right the Buddha
sees a guy calling somebody stupid
someone who reached nirvana sees a guy
calling somebody stupid uh someone who
saw Ultimate Reality directly sees a guy
calling somebody stupid and a guy who
has no clue about anything we just got
off one of those tears ships and is
headed to Atlantis I also see a guy
calling something stupid that's all
right it appears that way and they take
it that way am I right
all four am I okay yeah it's Pomona it's
there okay number two
uh
sorry which one of them
sees somebody coming from their own side
and takes them to be coming from their
own side let's go to the four people
okay they take the guys they see the guy
the guy appears to be coming from his
own son and they take it to be that way
okay so number one that's the guy who's
got off the tour ship headed Frontline
does he see the guy
does the guy have clearly him to be kind
of friends outside he takes it that way
yes yes how about the guy who saw
emptiness directly
does the guy appear to be coming from
his own stuff now this is delicate this
is important okay after you come out of
your first direct perception of Ultimate
Reality the world slips back into
appearing to come from itself
the world does appear
to a person who has agreed to be vegan
can't do to be coming from its own sight
but they don't
take it to be that way anymore
so that's a very difficult state to be
in you don't believe what's going on you
see it that way but you don't believe it
anymore it looks like the guy is coming
from his own side but I know better
but you can't stop how he's appearing
okay that's that's okay it's very
beautiful teaching uh about Nirvana
a person who raising your mind
does the guy appear to be coming from
his own side to a person who reached
Nevada I gotta check
hahaha
yeah you're right
no you're not right
yeah still appears to be
but they don't take it to be that way
and they have no what do you call it
cease to do it to do that anymore okay
that's dark
so they don't have number two okay
number three
uh
who oh how about a Buddha
how about enlighten me does the guy
appear to be coming from his own side
turn it like me no no no
and do they take him to be coming from
the sunset no no because I mean he's not
even appearing that way anymore okay all
right got it
this is beautiful if you can go through
this what do you call it permutations
then you're then you understand Ultimate
Reality okay third one this is hard
I grasped that the people I used to get
angry at were never there
I grasp I understand that every person I
ever got angry at in my whole life there
was nobody there
okay meaning what
a guy who was kind of his Alzheimer's
family there but you cannot get angry at
any other person the barometer
of whether you understand the other
person is whether you can get angry at
them because if you can you have a video
you cannot get angry at a person without
a video it's not possible without
misunderstanding who they are you cannot
get angry it's very interesting
I'll say that one more time you could
never be jealous or angry or upset at a
person unless you are misunderstanding
who they are
it's not possible it's it's it's pretty
cool that means you could get rid of
your anger and your irritation forever
you see okay so number two
the guy who just got off the turnship
does the guy appear to not be coming
from his own side no
does he take him not to be coming from
these ones go ahead to the guy who just
saw emptiness Ultimate Reality directly
that's the guy appear to not be coming
from his own side no yeah
no he still appears wrong he's still he
still appears to be coming from some
time but now this guy is not gonna okay
take him as coming from the sunset he
takes him to be not coming from his own
side
but he doesn't appear to not be coming
from his own son okay this is for the
eyeshadow people okay I'm saying the
rest you were asleep by now okay
got it
this is now what about a guy who
distribution their mother
the same
yeah it's the same thing
um
yeah uh no longer sorry hey up here the
guy yeah the guy appears to be not
coming from so I don't know what
attention that way all right okay we got
one more all right
he came from me he came to me to the guy
who got off the boat and he set him for
Atlantis and somebody calls him stupid
does he does the guy appearing to be
coming from his past karmic seats no
because he never heard of past card
does he take him to be that way good
good you're all there it's amazing okay
I'm having trouble
uh the guy who started doing this
directly uh when he when somebody yells
at him does he think does the guy appear
to him to be coming from his own karmic
suits no no
but does he take him to be there yeah
yeah you see what we're saying is that
for a person who just saw Ultimate
Reality he's not good enough yet at that
kind of thinking to pull it up in an
incident it's not fast enough here it
doesn't have enough practice yet he just
saw Ultimate Reality yesterday okay then
some guy comes up and says you're stupid
and his mind
I'm not coming from his sis but his his
understanding says well wait wait wait
wait don't get angry we saw yesterday
he's really coming from your own seeds
see it takes time for him to to pull out
his worldview and not get and not yell
back he'll probably say no yours
are they
even though the guy doesn't appear to be
coming from his own mind he understands
that he is coming from his own mind but
he hasn't been practicing that
perception of Ultimate Reality
frequently enough to catch how he's
coming from his own mind in the moment
that he's coming from the sounds like
when you get good
at the meditation on Ultimate Reality
you can watch a person who's yelling at
you come tell me your mind
you know it's not an intellectual Thing
You observe him coming out of your mind
okay then tell you the anger
you can get angry at yourself you know
so there's a point at which your
meditation is so good that when someone
yells at you you actually see that they
are coming you actually watch how
they're coming out of your life and then
there's no problem okay got it
all right
now something else
now now last thing okay we have a few
minutes left
where does compassion fit into all this
you see where does love fit into all
this and it's a huge huge debate in
British schools you know
if I don't have love
for other people if I'm not motivated by
a concerned for the welfare of all the
living creatures of the world is it even
possible to see Ultimate Reality
could I make the necessary seats in my
mind to see Ultimate Reality the
question comes up in in Buddhism
without compassion
is it possible to plant enough seeds of
understanding to get what I'm saying
tonight
if you had no
care for other people at all would you
be able to understand what I just said
what do you think
the highest goals say you can
it's possible it's not good but it's
possible it's possible
to like almost like a physicist
understands that the floor is not real
with no care about other people they'd
like to make a bomb
uh they can they can reach those deep
understandings without compassion it's
possible it's possible to manipulate the
laws of karma to your own uses in a in a
lousy half hearted way
without compassion it's possible
like a physicist who makes it who really
gets a deep insight into atomic theory
and then makes a bomb
to kill millions of people is possible
they can have deep insights intellectual
insights
without compassion it's possible okay
but
you cannot
get to the point between Nirvana and
Enlightenment without compassion you
can't go the extra step
from it from him appearing to come from
his own side to him no longer appearing
to come from his own side that extra
step cannot be done unless you have
compassion in your mind it's not
possible okay in this tradition you
cannot become an enlightened being
which means you cannot really grasp the
deepest workings of reality unless you
have compassion unless you're doing it
for somebody else
good
we call Body children right ultimate
love
it's not possible to have the deepest
realizations of things without ultimate
love it's not possible okay so that's
just the
fact of the universe okay what does
ultimate love mean
I see yourself in everything
almost
you're cool enough there okay
try to get this Theory okay try to get
this feeling every single person let's
pretend you're standing above the world
with your Guru okay it's always happens
with your Guru you actually Guru son you
are such a hard longest side
this is the way it always goes at the
end okay and you are standing about the
whole planet
like you're standing on the atmosphere
okay you're standing on the top of the
atmosphere with your heart not my head
it's fine just imagine your feet are on
the on the last part of the air
okay and you're looking down on the
world that you take care of
this is your this world is your
responsibility and you are watching the
globespin
and you are watching Dom
across from the what is it East to the
West right it's going from Europe to
you know China or whatever you are
watching the dawn
across the planet and then because
you're already enlightened you see six
billion people get up
you know some of them are like me you
know they're they're like snooze snooze
you know and then some are jumping out
of bed they have high hopes for a good
day you know some are all some are young
some are women some of them you know
animals are waking up also someone going
to bed and
I have coyotes around there I go to bed
and talk about those people
so you watch the world get up six
billion humans right
foreign
every single
action taken by every single person who
gets out of bed as you are watching is
mistake
from brushing their teeth to building uh
an Empire
every single action is mistake
everything they ever do is mistaken
and everything they ever see is mistake
so you gotta appreciate that
the breadth of Avidia you have to
appreciate
how how much of what you're doing is
everything everything
you ever did was wrong
okay every time you turn on a light
every time you ate a meal every time you
spoke to someone
it was mistaken
and
and then
and it must lead to pain
it must lead to pain and then imagine
standing over a world of six billion
people and knowing the only reason they
suffer is because they're seeing
something that was never there
okay it's a tragedy it's a global
tragedy you are standing with your heart
Guru Lana over a world your vision
Enlightenment you're looking down
and you have this intense realization
that that that all the suffering that
ever happens in the world was
unnecessary it was just a way of
thinking that was wrong you see like the
whole planet could be fixed
in a few decades 10 years 15 years
if people just understood what was going
on
you see the whole world would be fixed
easily how would you make money
just give it with the proper uh
intention and the proper knowledge
you can make money and cancer
you could stop cancer I have students
who uh
they're getting like unreasonably old
my friend I have this lady friend I am
just oh seven is something she insists
on coming out and building Adobe
buildings with us 50 pound Adobe blocks
she's like how tall is she
is she five feet yeah something like
that maybe five feet and she got cancer
20 years ago and he got rid of him
it's not necessary and
all the suffering is not necessary all
those things are wrong all those things
didn't have to happen you see what I
mean
and if they just understood a few things
everyone could be wealthy and everyone
could be healthy
and and your body would change the light
okay so that feeling
that oh if people could figure out this
thing that we've been talking about
how the person's not coming from their
son if people could figure that out
then there wouldn't be any suffering in
the world nobody would suffer at all
and then that feeling
that that's possible that's compassion
okay that vision
of a whole planet of people and no one's
suffering anymore no one getting old no
one fighting no one hungry everyone has
anything they want come on Damon uh
this is time possible if you understand
what we've been talking about the guy
who called you stupid if you understand
him
you could change the entire world with
no longer suffer so to see them suffer
to see
to see people to see 69 people suffering
would cause you sadness
to see six billion people suffer
where they didn't have to would cause
compassion got it God you feel a
difference okay
if people understood what we said about
the stupid guy
that no there would be no death in this
room at all and no one would suffer and
no one would be hungry okay try to feel
that
if you have that feeling in your heart
when you finally see emptiness directly
when you finally see the real nature of
the guy
then you can become in life
if you have that kind of feeling in your
heart well I could change six billion
people's lives
if you have bad feeling in your heart
when you see them that the guy you
thought was there was not there okay
then you become a Buddha the power of
the compassion uh is the difference
between Nirvana all right
good
that's oh
the guy
who's calling you stupid who's not your
fault
which is the only one you can get angry
at was never there
right there because everything's
informed sorry
so your wife was right
no I mean what I mean is everything good
is also your fault I mean some people
came to me and they said look I'm
depressed enough already now you tell me
everything's messed up I said no no
every good thing is your phone clear
remember
you you made him
who created him you created the first
one okay and it's a really beautiful
place okay last thing
um
I wanted to thank everybody to answer
them for having us one more time
and we're very grateful and Brook really
has tested me
until we said we would come back next
time we're talking about that
and then um
I have one last thing that I'd like to
talk to you about so any I mean the
first thing is that I say every year
that the people who live here and the
people who have come here for the
teacher training uh you are so lucky
this is I I travel constantly
and uh my whole life is one long gentler
and uh
and this is this is probably the most
beautiful ashram in the world that I've
ever seen and you're very lucky you're
really lucky and you know if you live
here you get spoiled and you think well
I don't like the dishwashing and stuff
like that but but
you're the luckiest people in the world
I think you're the luckiest people in
the world
except for me but anyway
no I have my llama but uh you're really
lucky and you should
you should understand how lucky you are
and don't
don't anytime you have a doubt or
anytime anything seems not perfect just
tell yourself to shut up
really and not because of the Sun and
the Earth
but uh it's the teaching is something I
think that the choice is authentic it's
it's
guided very compassionately it's a
beautiful place teaching is good the
yoga is good everything is is authentic
and compassionate and you're very lucky
to even when you're tired you shouldn't
forget that that's one thing I like to
say secondly I'd like to ask a favor
okay so I was in Hong Kong
because I saw the thing about the
earthquake in Japan I I wrote to my
friends there we have friends in the
yoga community in Japan and we go there
and we teach a lot and um
so we called them and then we said how
are things you know and they said
because they come to our programs in
Mexico a lot because they can't get into
the U.S because I'm Homeland security
uh so last last time in Mexico right a
nice Japanese group and I have a you
know a good group of our friends from
Japan King
to the program in Mexico and it was uh
it was that November
right November I think November
and so you know
we call them to ask how is everybody
okay
and they say Kazumi
uh who's one of the women who came and
said she her grandmother
lives on the Northeast Coast and as soon
as she heard there might be a tsunami
she went together
and she she never came back
she's gone you know and
and it's weird to to do yoga to do yoga
next to somebody and then know that
they're gone you know and she went to
try to help her grandmother and they
both got caught
and then um
and then we did a Skype
program we did some prayers we did
Buddhist prayers for the Dead
uh by Skype and then one of the ladies
son was
coffee
and then they realized that he had been
drinking the water
in Tokyo which is now not sent for
children children should not drink the
water and don't care there's no other
water
it's all sold out
the health today with the water there's
no choice so you know we're on this
video conference we're doing prayers
together consuming is not there anymore
and uh
and the children are already getting
something sick and that's not going to
stop for 20 30 years it's gonna keep
going and um so I don't know we said
I said can we send you some money can we
say are you doing anything they said
yeah our yoga studio is sending people
to the north with blankets and food and
they're still doing that okay as we
speak they are still going into the
radiation
and taking blankets and food from my
yoga studio
so I would I'm collecting money for them
I'm asking people to help okay we can't
do much okay it doesn't mean anything
it's not gonna
I feel like it's more of a gesture to
say we're with you and we love you and
we care about you you see I I don't
think whatever we